

# **Soufiane Mghanen**

## **Profile**

Enthusiastic Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience working in both start-ups and international corporate industries. With exposure to the complete product development lifecycle, I am eager to apply and share what I have learnt into more successful projects. Looking for opportunities in an environment where I can develop and grow further as an individual and a professional.

# **Key Skills**

- + Full stack development comfortable working with both Backend and Frontend stacks.
- + Strong understanding and practice of Agile methodologies to ensure effective feedback loops are established with the end client.
- + Work across functional and project teams to ensure continuous operation of build and test systems.
- + Proactively seek opportunities to improve internal team processes and toolset usage.

# **Recent Technology Stack**

- **+ Backend:** golang, python, PHP, GraphQl, Django, Celery.
- + Frontend: HTM5L, CSS3, ReactJs, Redux.
- + **DEVOPS:** Git, Docker, Kubernetes, TravisCI, AWS, GCP, Helm, Istio.
- + DATABASES: PostgresSQL, MySQL, Redis, Mongo, ElasticSearch, RabbitMQ.
- + SYSADMIN: CentOS, Bash scripting, Windows Server, Powershell.
- + SDLC: Scrum, TDD, Kanban, Jira.

# **Employment History**

Jan 2017 - May 2019

FullStack Engineer - Schibsted Media Group

Main technology used: Golang, PHP, ReactJs, PostgresSQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, C++.

- + Contributed to an atmosphere of cross-functional teamwork within the organization's emerging Agile delivery lifecycle.
- + Contributed to the efforts of the company to migrate towards a microservices oriented architecture.
- + Collaborated with cross teams, engineering and product managers to design, build and deliver scalable solutions.
- + Participated in identifying and improving performance bottlenecks in the existing stack.

#### Apr 2015 - Dec 2016

#### FullStack Engineer - CapValue Consulting

Main technology used: Python, Django, DRF, PostgresSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ, Angular.

- + Designed and implemented a scalable distributed task processing infrastructure.
- + Designed and implemented a REST API to manage task queuing and access results.
- + Designed and built a Single Page Application as an interface for working with tasks.
- + Configured CI/CD pipelines to manage code and deployments.
- + Mentored and pair programmed with a small team of junior developers.

#### Nov 2013 - Apr 2015

### IT Support Technician - Marjane Holding

Main technology used: Active Directory, Powershell, Bash, File Servers, Gold ERP.

- + Provided desktop support, account maintenance and printing assistance.
- + Prioritised and managed many open cases within agreed time limits to callouts.
- + Installed and configured computer hardware, operating systems and applications.
- + Monitored and managed backups and restores for multiple application servers.

#### Nov 2012 - Jul 2013

### Junior Software engineer - IHM Technologies

Main technology used: C#, ASP.Net, Microsoft SQL Server, Drupal.

- + Attended meetings with clients and discussed their requirements and proposed solutions with the project manager.
- + Contributed to time and resource estimates to assist in the planning of projects.
- + Worked as part of a small software development team to produce technical work, as directed by the project manager and the software team leader.
- + Worked closely with other senior engineers to develop the best technical design and approach for new product development.

### **Education**

2012 - 2014	University Hassan 1er, Morocco	MSc. Management Information Systems
2011 - 2012	University Hassan 1er, Morocco	BSc. IT and Industrial Management
2006 - 2008	Institute of Technology, Morocco	EngTech. Industrial Automation and Control

### **Certifications**

- + Microsoft Certified Professional (Installing and Configuring Windows server 2012).
- + ITIL V3 Foundation.

# Languages

- **+ English:** Full professional proficiency.
- + French: Full professional proficiency.
- + Arabic: Native proficiency.